SYLVIA RAMIREZ SOTO

CONTACT



210-387-6475



Sylvia Ramirez Soto



⊠ ghm766@my.utsa.edu

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sylviaramir ezsoto/

PROFILE

In the last twenty years, I have worked in the cosmetic industry. I have been a part of some great companies that I have helped launch to be successful in major retailers, such as Nordstrom and Neiman Marcus. A couple of those brands are Maison Francis Kurkdijian and Beauty Bio. The experience I have harnessed in the beauty industry will help in a new career I am aspiring to, full stack web developer.

SKILLS

- **CUSTOMER SERVICE**
- PRODUCT LAUNCH
- **TEAM BUILDING**
- PRODUCT TRAINING
- SALES
- HTML5
- CASCADING STYLE SHEETS (CSS)
- WEB DEVELOPMENT

EDUCATION

UTSA Coding Bootcamp

January 2020 - July 2020

Front end and back end certification for full stack web development. Utilizing HTML, Cascading Style Sheets (CSS), JavaScript, MySQL, Node, Express, MongoDB, and Sequelize.

EXPERIENCE

Beauty Bio

April 2018 - Present

As a freelance consultant, I have launched the Beauty Bio brand at Nordstrom and Neiman Marcus La Cantera. It is a skincare company with a patented skincare tool, the GloPro. Through product training and event execution, both retailers have placed in the top 10 for the company. There was a personal appearance at Neiman Marcus July 2019. The goal was \$10,000 and a stretch goal of \$15,000 was given. The event did \$22,000. Through a personalized customer service experience, I have been able to build a loyal client base.

Maison Francis Kurkdjian

July 2014 - September 2018

Launched the Maison Francis Kurkdjian brand at Neiman Marcus at La Cantera. For threes straight years, the brand had a double-digit increase, and ranked 7 out of 47 stores. Demonstrated product knowledge and trained associates. Executed events in store and aided sellers to better facilitate the closing a sale. As a customer service leader, I was able to build a loyal client base.

Nordstrom La Cantera

February 2009 - June 2014

University of Texas at San Antonio

September 1987 – December 1992 September 2006 – May 2008

BA of History with a post teaching certificate in composite Social Studies $8^{th}-12^{th}$ grade. Extracurricular activities included, student coordinator for Amnesty International – UTSA Chapter, Vice President for People for Choice, and a member of MeCHa, the Mexican – American student organization.

Started at Nordstrom La Cantera as a Beauty Advisor for Bobbi Brown Cosmetic and Skincare Company. In a few months, promoted to Business Manager for Advanced Skincare Technology. I managed 17 brands and executed a \$41,000 event for the brand Sensual Solutions in April 2010. The #1 corporate event at Nordstrom for the brand. Then offered the position of Business Manager for Kiehl's since 1851. I left Nordstrom when I was recruited to work at Neiman Marcus.